{"text": "Bangladesh would consider an out-of-court settlement with a bank in the Philippines over $81 million stolen from its accounts in New York by hackers who wired the money to Manila, Bangladesh central bank officials said on Thursday. In one of the world's biggest cyber heists, the hackers stole the Bangladesh Bank money held at the New York Fed in February 2016 using fraudulent orders on the SWIFT payments system and sent it to Rizal Commercial Banking Corp . From there, it disappeared into the casino industry in the Philippines. No one has been charged for the heist despite an international investigation and two years of finger-pointing among Bangladesh, Philippines, the Fed and SWIFT. There is an option before us to settle the issue out of court, a senior official at Bangladesh's central bank told Reuters. The official, who declined to be identified, cited as a precedent an out-of-court settlement in February reached by Ecuador's Banco del Austro and Wells Fargo over a 2015 cyber heist. Bangladesh's Finance Minister Abul Maal Abdul Muhith on Thursday met Carlos Dominguez, Finance Secretary of the Philippines, on the sidelines of a four-day annual meeting of the Asian Development Bank in Manila to discuss the cyber heist, said two senior central bank officials close to the issue. Bangladesh is yet to take legal action but had planned a suit to recover $66 million. Around $15 million has been recovered from a Manila junket operator, a job that involves marketing casinos to VIPs. We will try for all possible options to recover our stolen money, the officials added. There was no immediate comment from Dominguez or Rizal bank in Manila.", "labels": [[72, 83, "GPE"], [89, 100, "MONEY"], [129, 137, "GPE"], [172, 178, "GPE"], [222, 230, "DATE"], [235, 238, "CARDINAL"], [298, 313, "ORG"], [328, 344, "ORG"], [348, 361, "DATE"], [393, 398, "ORG"], [430, 459, "ORG"], [521, 532, "GPE"], [615, 624, "DATE"], [650, 660, "GPE"], [662, 673, "GPE"], [679, 682, "ORG"], [687, 692, "ORG"], [782, 792, "ORG"], [813, 820, "ORG"], [918, 926, "DATE"], [938, 945, "GPE"], [948, 964, "ORG"], [969, 980, "ORG"], [988, 992, "DATE"], [1036, 1058, "PERSON"], [1062, 1070, "DATE"], [1075, 1091, "PERSON"], [1093, 1100, "ORG"], [1118, 1129, "GPE"], [1153, 1161, "DATE"], [1162, 1168, "DATE"], [1180, 1206, "ORG"], [1210, 1216, "GPE"], [1250, 1253, "CARDINAL"], [1377, 1388, "MONEY"], [1390, 1408, "MONEY"], [1435, 1441, "GPE"], [1633, 1651, "ORG"], [1660, 1666, "GPE"]]}
{"text": "The seven detainees held by the DB police over question paper leak on December 8, 2018 Collected USB drives, Bluetooth devices, SIM cards and mobile phones were also recovered in the drive Detective Branch (DB) of Police has detained seven people for their alleged involvement in leaking question papers of recruitment examinations through electronic devices. Shohel Rana, Mahmudul, Ansarul Islam, Debasis, Rabiul Auwal, Rajiur Rahman and Rejaul Karim were arrested from Dhaka's Mirpur, Kalabagan and Shiddeshwari areas on Friday. The detainees were also allegedly involved in helping people cheat in the recruitment test for Department of Narcotics Control (DNC). The DB police also recovered USB drives, Bluetooth devices, SIM cards and mobile phones from the possession of the detainees. DMP Deputy Commissioner Masudur Rahman, in a press briefing on Saturday, said: “Among the detainees, Shohel has been held before for the same offense, but he had secured bail later.” He said they were also involved in leaking question papers of different recruitment examinations. Masudur Rahman said in the preliminary interrogation, they learned that this time they had leaked the question papers of DNC recruitment test. He said: “We also found out that among the detainees, three sat for the exam with electronic devices. “Later, they sent the question papers to the other four, who solved the problem and resend the solutions to their clients.” The deputy commissioner said they charged Tk5 to 10 lakh for the work. However, the payments were made after the clients passed their exams. He said: “We filed a case against with Ramna police station. We have submitted a request to the court seeking permission for remanding them.”", "labels": [[4, 9, "CARDINAL"], [70, 86, "DATE"], [128, 131, "ORG"], [189, 205, "ORG"], [214, 220, "ORG"], [234, 239, "CARDINAL"], [360, 371, "PERSON"], [373, 381, "PERSON"], [383, 396, "PERSON"], [398, 405, "ORG"], [407, 419, "ORG"], [421, 434, "PERSON"], [439, 451, "PERSON"], [471, 476, "PERSON"], [487, 496, "PERSON"], [501, 513, "ORG"], [523, 529, "DATE"], [626, 657, "ORG"], [659, 662, "ORG"], [694, 697, "ORG"], [706, 715, "ORG"], [725, 728, "ORG"], [791, 794, "ORG"], [815, 829, "PERSON"], [854, 862, "DATE"], [892, 898, "PERSON"], [1072, 1086, "PERSON"], [1193, 1196, "ORG"], [1269, 1274, "CARDINAL"], [1368, 1372, "CARDINAL"], [1490, 1492, "CARDINAL"], [1621, 1626, "NORP"]]}
{"text": "Police have arrested the two main suspects of an assault case in which a married couple was beaten up in front of shop at the Api-Api Centre here. — iStock.com pic via AFP KOTA KINABALU, June 6 — Police have arrested the two main suspects of an assault case in which a married couple was beaten up in front of shop at the Api-Api Centre here, an incident that was caught on camera and went viral. Kota Kinabalu acting district police chief Supt George Abd Rakman said the suspects, aged 67 and 37 respectively, were apprehended on Tuesday, two days after the 1am incident on June 2. “The two men will be charged in court tomorrow and we are still looking for several other individuals involved in the incident,” he said in a statement here, today. Footage from a closed-circuit television camera (CCTV) that later went viral on social media showed a couple being beaten up in front of shop at the Api-Api Centre. George said the male victim, a Pakistani and his wife were assaulted by a group of individuals due to property rental issues. “Just before the incident, the victims, who were renting the property concerned, were approached by a woman and man, and a discussion among them turned into a heated argument before escalating into a physical fight that involved the father and brother of the landlord,” George said. The case is being investigated under Section 147 of the Penal Code which provides for a jail term of up to two years, or a fine, or both, upon conviction. — Bernama", "labels": [[25, 28, "CARDINAL"], [122, 140, "FAC"], [168, 185, "PERSON"], [187, 193, "DATE"], [221, 224, "CARDINAL"], [318, 336, "FAC"], [397, 410, "PERSON"], [440, 462, "PERSON"], [487, 489, "CARDINAL"], [494, 496, "CARDINAL"], [531, 538, "DATE"], [540, 548, "DATE"], [559, 562, "QUANTITY"], [575, 581, "DATE"], [588, 591, "CARDINAL"], [621, 629, "DATE"], [741, 746, "DATE"], [797, 801, "ORG"], [893, 911, "FAC"], [913, 919, "PERSON"], [944, 953, "NORP"], [1309, 1315, "PERSON"], [1359, 1370, "LAW"], [1374, 1388, "LAW"], [1423, 1438, "DATE"]]}
{"text": "MAKKAL Osai highlighted the plight of residents of Sungai Karangan near Gurun, Kedah, who have endured the pungent smell and the threat of worm infestation from a chicken farm for the past two years. Resident T. Murthy said they decided to organise public demonstrations after their complaints fell on deaf ears. “Some political leaders promised to find a solution during the last general election but nothing was done. “The pungent smell emanating from the chicken farm has caused many children to fall sick,” he said. Murthy added that the farm operator claimed that the company had ordered RM30,000 worth of machinery to reduce the problem. > The paper also reported that the Indian external affairs ministry had informed the Madras High Court that a Sri Lankan minister cannot be charged for a shooting case as he has diplomatic immunity. The ministry said the arrest of Sri Lanka's traditional industries and small enterprise development minister Douglas Devananda would affect relations between the two countries. Lawyer P. Pugazhendi had filed a petition asking the court to arrest Devananda during the latter's visit to India in June last year. Pugazhendi said Devananda, then a member of Sri Lanka's separatist Eelam People's Revolutionary Liberation Front, is wanted in a 1986 shootout and murder case in Chennai. In that incident, Devananda and several other Sri Lankan men had opened fire on local residents, killing one. He was also accused of kidnapping a boy in 1988. Other News & Views is compiled from the vernacular newspapers (Bahasa Malaysia, Chinese and Tamil dailies). As such, stories are grouped according to the respective language/medium. Where a paragraph begins with this > sign, it denotes a separate news item.", "labels": [[0, 11, "ORG"], [51, 66, "ORG"], [72, 77, "GPE"], [79, 84, "PERSON"], [180, 198, "DATE"], [200, 218, "PERSON"], [520, 526, "PERSON"], [679, 685, "NORP"], [725, 746, "ORG"], [754, 764, "GPE"], [875, 886, "GPE"], [952, 969, "PERSON"], [1005, 1008, "CARDINAL"], [1020, 1040, "PERSON"], [1089, 1098, "PERSON"], [1128, 1133, "GPE"], [1137, 1151, "DATE"], [1153, 1163, "GPE"], [1169, 1178, "PERSON"], [1197, 1208, "GPE"], [1220, 1265, "ORG"], [1282, 1286, "DATE"], [1315, 1322, "GPE"], [1342, 1351, "PERSON"], [1370, 1380, "GPE"], [1429, 1432, "CARDINAL"], [1477, 1481, "DATE"], [1489, 1501, "ORG"], [1553, 1561, "GPE"], [1563, 1570, "NORP"], [1575, 1580, "NORP"]]}
{"text": "A WIFE was dragged into a room, tied up and raped by her husband after an argument, reported Harian Metro. The man lost his temper when his 29-year-old wife refused to follow him to her mother's home for a kenduri (feast) as she wanted to go for a company dinner. According to a source, the husband, 29, got angry when he saw his wife getting ready to attend the dinner at their home in Pandan Indah in Ampang, Kuala Lumpur. “He tried to stop her from going as he wanted her to accompany him to his mother-in-law's place,” said the source. The husband blew his top when she refused to listen to him and tied her hands with a piece of cloth. “She was dragged into a room and forced to have sex,” he said, adding that the husband freed her before leaving. The victim lodged a report at the Pandan Indah police station. > A man claimed in the magistrate's court that he had to sell porn DVDs to support his family, reported Sinar Harian. Raziman Ramli, 24, pleaded guilty to selling the DVDs and was fined RM2,000 on Thursday. He was caught red-handed selling porn DVDs opposite a 24-hour sundry shop in Gelugor, Penang at about 8pm on May 22. Raziman was charged under Section 292 (A) of the Penal Code. Other News & Views is compiled from the vernacular newspapers (Bahasa Malaysia, Chinese and Tamil dailies). As such, stories are grouped according to the respective language/medium. Where a paragraph begins with this > sign, it denotes a separate news item.", "labels": [[2, 6, "ORG"], [93, 105, "PERSON"], [300, 302, "CARDINAL"], [387, 399, "LOC"], [403, 409, "GPE"], [411, 423, "GPE"], [788, 800, "ORG"], [935, 948, "PERSON"], [950, 952, "DATE"], [1003, 1010, "CARDINAL"], [1014, 1022, "DATE"], [1101, 1108, "GPE"], [1110, 1116, "GPE"], [1120, 1129, "QUANTITY"], [1133, 1139, "DATE"], [1141, 1148, "PERSON"], [1167, 1178, "LAW"], [1186, 1200, "LAW"], [1208, 1220, "ORG"], [1272, 1280, "GPE"], [1282, 1289, "NORP"], [1294, 1299, "NORP"]]}
{"text": "PETALING JAYA: The whereabouts of a Malaysian abducted in Ivory Coast almost five months ago still remains unknown. Pandian Chelliah, 47, his French boss and Sifca Group founder Yves Lambelin, Lambelin's assistant Raoul Adeossi from Benin and Novotel hotel's French director Stphane Frantz di Rippel were abducted from the same hotel in Abidjan on April 4 during the height of the civil unrest there. A Wisma Putra official said yesterday they were still looking for Pandian. “There has been no new leads but as far as we are concerned, he is still missing. We cannot say he is dead when there is no body, proof or information to verify the (local) reports. “We have requested information from the Ivorian government but there has been no response so far. His fate is still unknown and we do not want to speculate.” Ivory Coast media reports said forces aligned to ousted former president Laurent Gbagbo kidnapped the four men and took them to the presidential palace. Quoting the Justice Minister Jeannot Kouadio Ahoussou, the African media reported that the bodies of the four men were believed to have been wrapped in black plastic bags similar to those used to package bananas, before being thrown into a lagoon. The revelation was made following the arrest of the abductors. Two remains were subsequently found, but only Lambelin was positively identified. Pandian and Adeossi are still listed as missing. Pandian was the managing director of Sania, a subsidiary of Sifca which is the largest private company in the Ivory Coast. Pro-Gbagbo forces including militiamen, police commissioners and republican guards have been charged with the abduction of the four.", "labels": [[36, 45, "NORP"], [58, 69, "GPE"], [70, 92, "DATE"], [116, 132, "PERSON"], [134, 136, "DATE"], [142, 148, "NORP"], [158, 169, "ORG"], [178, 191, "PERSON"], [193, 201, "PERSON"], [214, 227, "PERSON"], [233, 238, "ORG"], [243, 250, "ORG"], [259, 265, "NORP"], [275, 289, "PERSON"], [293, 299, "ORG"], [337, 344, "GPE"], [348, 355, "DATE"], [403, 414, "ORG"], [429, 438, "DATE"], [467, 474, "NORP"], [698, 705, "NORP"], [816, 827, "GPE"], [889, 903, "ORG"], [918, 922, "CARDINAL"], [981, 988, "ORG"], [998, 1022, "PERSON"], [1028, 1035, "NORP"], [1074, 1078, "CARDINAL"], [1280, 1283, "CARDINAL"], [1326, 1334, "PERSON"], [1362, 1369, "NORP"], [1374, 1381, "PERSON"], [1411, 1418, "NORP"], [1448, 1453, "GPE"], [1471, 1476, "ORG"], [1517, 1532, "GPE"], [1534, 1544, "ORG"], [1661, 1665, "CARDINAL"]]}
{"text": "SEREMBAN: A man who walked into a service centre near here on the pretext of servicing his Perodua Myvi shocked patrons and the outlet owner when he drove away another customer's newly-serviced BMW. However, he was arrested the next morning while attempting to drive the car out of a parking lot outside a row of shophouses near his home in Sikamat near here. Police also seized two other vehicles parked near the rented home of the suspect a Mitsubishi Triton and a Kia Spectra. The Myvi was also reported stolen earlier. Preliminary investigations revealed that the suspect, in his early 40s, had gone on a spree, stealing several other cars including Honda, Toyota and Nissan models from service centres and workshops, state police chief Senior Asst Comm Datuk Osman Salleh said. “The thefts were reported in the Klang Valley in recent weeks. Investigations reveal this is a one-man show,” he told reporters yesterday. He added that the suspect, who was from Perak but did odd jobs in Kuala Lumpur, had been jailed twice for criminal offences. He had been renting the house here for the past three months. “His modus operandi was simple. He would observe happenings at a particular workshop or service centre, coolly walk in and just drive the car away,” he said, adding that there was a possibility that the stolen cars might have been cannibalised and sold to spare part dealers. SAC Osman advised those who had bought cars below the market value to notify the nearest police station as they might be driving stolen vehicles. Those found driving such vehicles can be charged with having stolen property.", "labels": [[91, 103, "PRODUCT"], [194, 197, "ORG"], [341, 348, "GPE"], [379, 382, "CARDINAL"], [443, 460, "LOC"], [467, 470, "ORG"], [484, 488, "PRODUCT"], [584, 593, "DATE"], [654, 659, "ORG"], [661, 667, "ORG"], [672, 678, "ORG"], [812, 828, "LOC"], [832, 844, "DATE"], [878, 881, "CARDINAL"], [911, 920, "DATE"], [962, 967, "PERSON"], [988, 1000, "GPE"], [1086, 1107, "DATE"], [1385, 1388, "ORG"]]}
{"text": "SUNGAI GOLOK (South Thailand): The Thai government announced Tuesday that it had paid compensation totalling RM60,000 to the six families of Malaysians killed in the series of bomb blasts, here, in September. Sungai Golok deputy security officer, Santi Chuduang said RM5,000 was also allocated to five Malaysians who were injured in the incident. The compensation was given to them in October and November. This shows the Thai government's concern for the victims and their families, he told Malaysian reporters after a security meeting and demonstration in Kampung Arissra, here. He said each family of the six Malaysians killed were given RM10,000 while the injured received RM1,000 each. The six Malaysians killed here on Sept 16 were Wong Kai Sean, 3, his grandfather, Wong Hong Yep, 64, Chan Yau Wing, 52, Foong Too Keh, 45, Chan Yew Soon, 63, and Ng Sai Kai, 63. Injured were Lai Yok Long, Wong Wai Siong, Wee It Cheng, Phoo King Kuang and Cheng Yew Mang. Chuduang, who is also Sungai Golok district officer, however, said the compensation would be increased if the injuries became serious and caused permanent disability. Meanwhile, Malaysians have been told not to worry about coming here as the authorities are always taking measures to ensure security in Sungai Golok. Sungai Golok deputy police chief Lt Col. Toweesak Tongsangsee said a 26-year-old Thai man had been charged over the bombings. He said police were hunting for at least 10 individuals believed to be involved in the bombings. We seek cooperation including from the Malaysian authorities if they know the identity of the people we are looking for, he said. - Bernama", "labels": [[14, 28, "GPE"], [35, 39, "NORP"], [61, 68, "DATE"], [125, 128, "CARDINAL"], [141, 151, "NORP"], [198, 207, "DATE"], [209, 221, "ORG"], [247, 261, "PERSON"], [267, 274, "CARDINAL"], [297, 301, "CARDINAL"], [302, 312, "NORP"], [387, 394, "DATE"], [399, 407, "DATE"], [424, 428, "NORP"], [496, 505, "NORP"], [562, 577, "GPE"], [612, 615, "CARDINAL"], [616, 626, "NORP"], [681, 688, "NORP"], [699, 702, "CARDINAL"], [703, 713, "NORP"], [729, 736, "DATE"], [742, 755, "PERSON"], [757, 758, "DATE"], [777, 790, "PERSON"], [792, 794, "DATE"], [796, 809, "PERSON"], [811, 813, "DATE"], [815, 828, "PERSON"], [830, 832, "DATE"], [834, 847, "PERSON"], [849, 851, "DATE"], [857, 867, "PERSON"], [869, 871, "DATE"], [886, 898, "PERSON"], [900, 914, "PERSON"], [916, 928, "PERSON"], [930, 945, "PERSON"], [950, 964, "PERSON"], [966, 974, "PERSON"], [988, 1000, "ORG"], [1144, 1154, "NORP"], [1269, 1281, "ORG"], [1283, 1295, "ORG"], [1316, 1322, "PERSON"], [1324, 1344, "PERSON"], [1364, 1368, "NORP"], [1441, 1452, "CARDINAL"], [1547, 1556, "NORP"]]}
{"text": "More than 200 customers, many wearing student uniforms, were found inside Space pub in Bang Khen district, Bangkok early Wednesday. 120 of them tested positive for drugs. (Photo taken from www.fm91bkk.com) A total of 120 pub-goers tested positive for drugs and packages of narcotics seized during a police raid on a pub in Bangkok’s Bang Khen district in the early hours of Wednesday A combined team of city police and narcotics suppression officials raided Space pub on Pradit Manutham Road in Tha Raeng area at around 3am. Hundreds of people, mostly dressed in student uniforms, were found dancing and drinking inside the one-storey pub. They fled in panic, but around 200 pub-goers were soon rounded up. Small packages of drugs, including ecstasy, ketamine and electronic cigarettes, were found scattered around the area, Thai media reported. Sumet Ruamkaew, 28, admitted to being the pub's manager, police said. Pol Col Jirakrit Jarunpat, commander of the police's women and children welfare division, who led the raid, said the pub had been in operation for two months. Police received information that narcotics were being used inside the venue, and coordinated with other agencies to conduct the raid. No customers aged under 18 were found inside. All the pub-goers were asked to submit urine tests and 120 of them -- including 70 men and 50 women -- tested positive for drugs. The pub would be ordered closed for 5 years, said Pol Col Jirakrit. Police initially charged the pub manager with operating the pub illegally, operating beyond legal opening hours and illegal sales of alcohol in violation of an order issued by the National Council for Peace and Order.", "labels": [[0, 13, "CARDINAL"], [87, 96, "PERSON"], [107, 114, "GPE"], [115, 130, "DATE"], [132, 135, "CARDINAL"], [217, 220, "CARDINAL"], [323, 330, "GPE"], [333, 342, "PERSON"], [355, 370, "TIME"], [374, 383, "DATE"], [471, 491, "ORG"], [495, 504, "GPE"], [525, 533, "CARDINAL"], [624, 627, "CARDINAL"], [671, 674, "CARDINAL"], [825, 829, "NORP"], [846, 860, "PERSON"], [862, 864, "DATE"], [1063, 1073, "DATE"], [1227, 1235, "DATE"], [1310, 1313, "CARDINAL"], [1335, 1337, "CARDINAL"], [1346, 1348, "CARDINAL"], [1421, 1428, "DATE"], [1435, 1451, "PERSON"], [1629, 1669, "ORG"]]}
{"text": "SHAH ALAM: A police computer forensic analyst in the murder trial of Datuk Sosilawati Lawiya and three others said he received 11 handphones belonging to two of the victims. Asst Supt Mohd Zulkifly Mohd Isa, 31, from Bukit Aman, testified that he received two BlackBerry 9700 handphones for analysis from investigating officer ASP Ishak Yaakob on Sept 17 last year. It was earlier testified that two black and white BlackBerry handphones, belonging to bank officer Noorhisham Mohammad and lawyer Ahmad Kamil Abdul Karim respectively, were recovered at a water lock near the Banting wet market. Both Noorhisham and Ahmad Kamil went missing with Sosilawati and her driver Kamaruddin Shamsuddin on Aug 30, 2010, after telling their families and friends that they were going to Banting to discuss a land deal. ASP Mohd Zulkifly said the two BlackBerry units were in a package. “The devices were misted over inside. I took them out and used a blower to dry them. I did this at the handphone lab,” said the witness. On Sept 17 and 20 last year, ASP Mohd Zulkifly received other exhibits from ASP Ishak and a colleague known as Insp Suzana. The exhibits were several SIM cards, handphone memory cards (microSD and MMC types), handphone batteries and an 8GB Data Traveler USB flash drive. On Sept 23, 2010, ASP Mohd Zulkifly returned the exhibits to Insp Suzana. He is the 76th witness testifying in the trial against former lawyer N. Pathmanabhan and three of his farm hands – T. Thilaiyalagan, R. Matan and R. Kathavarayan. The four are charged with the murder of Sosilawati, 47, Kamaruddin, 44, Noorhisham, 38, and Ahmad Kamil, 32. The hearing continues today.", "labels": [[69, 92, "ORG"], [97, 102, "CARDINAL"], [127, 129, "CARDINAL"], [154, 157, "CARDINAL"], [174, 206, "PERSON"], [208, 210, "DATE"], [217, 227, "PERSON"], [256, 259, "CARDINAL"], [260, 275, "ORG"], [327, 330, "ORG"], [347, 364, "DATE"], [396, 399, "CARDINAL"], [416, 426, "ORG"], [465, 484, "PERSON"], [496, 519, "PERSON"], [599, 609, "PERSON"], [614, 625, "PERSON"], [644, 654, "GPE"], [670, 691, "PERSON"], [695, 707, "DATE"], [810, 823, "PERSON"], [833, 836, "CARDINAL"], [837, 847, "ORG"], [1013, 1037, "DATE"], [1039, 1042, "ORG"], [1043, 1056, "PERSON"], [1086, 1095, "ORG"], [1121, 1132, "PERSON"], [1160, 1163, "ORG"], [1207, 1210, "ORG"], [1246, 1247, "CARDINAL"], [1247, 1249, "NORP"], [1284, 1297, "DATE"], [1299, 1316, "ORG"], [1342, 1353, "ORG"], [1424, 1439, "PERSON"], [1444, 1449, "CARDINAL"], [1470, 1486, "PERSON"], [1488, 1496, "PERSON"], [1501, 1516, "PERSON"], [1522, 1526, "CARDINAL"], [1558, 1568, "GPE"], [1570, 1572, "DATE"], [1574, 1584, "PERSON"], [1586, 1588, "DATE"], [1590, 1600, "PERSON"], [1602, 1604, "DATE"], [1610, 1621, "PERSON"], [1623, 1625, "DATE"], [1649, 1654, "DATE"]]}
{"text": "KUALA LUMPUR: A German engineer was charged in the Sessions Court here with causing grievous hurt to a Yahoo Malaysia sales manager. Felix Sebastian, 37, pleaded not guilty before judge Mahmud Abdullah. He is alleged to have seriously injured a friend, Ashvin Danny Holtkamp, 24, on his left eye with a glass mug at Club 21, Bangsar Shopping Centre in Bangsar between 12am and 12.30am on Dec 4. The charge under Section 326 of the Penal Code carries a maximum 20 years' jail and fine or whipping upon conviction. Prosecuting officer Supt R.Munusamy requested of the court to set bail at RM50,000 in two local sureties and for the accused's passport to be impounded. Sebastian's counsel S.Selva Balan mitigated for the sum to be reduced to RM5,000 and for the accused to keep his passport as he had already booked a flight last Oct 24 to return to Germany to celebrate Christmas with his two children from his ex-wife. He will surrender his passport to the court on the second week of Feb 2012, counsel requested. The court decided in the prosecution's favour and imposed a RM50,000 bail in two local sureties and for the accused to surrender his passport to the court and report to the nearest police station every two weeks until disposal of the case. Nevertheless, Mahmud allowed the defence's application for temporary release of the passport to enable the accused to return to his country on condition he surrendered the document back to the court on or before Feb 1 next year upon returning to Malaysia. The case has been fixed for re-mention on Feb 2, 2012. BERNAMA", "labels": [[0, 5, "ORG"], [16, 22, "NORP"], [47, 65, "ORG"], [103, 117, "LOC"], [133, 148, "PERSON"], [150, 152, "DATE"], [186, 201, "PERSON"], [260, 274, "PERSON"], [276, 278, "DATE"], [316, 323, "FAC"], [325, 348, "FAC"], [352, 359, "GPE"], [368, 370, "CARDINAL"], [412, 423, "LAW"], [427, 441, "LAW"], [460, 469, "DATE"], [533, 537, "ORG"], [587, 595, "PRODUCT"], [599, 602, "CARDINAL"], [666, 675, "NORP"], [694, 699, "PERSON"], [822, 833, "DATE"], [847, 854, "GPE"], [868, 877, "DATE"], [887, 890, "CARDINAL"], [967, 994, "DATE"], [1077, 1085, "PRODUCT"], [1094, 1097, "CARDINAL"], [1213, 1228, "DATE"], [1271, 1277, "PERSON"], [1469, 1484, "DATE"], [1503, 1511, "GPE"], [1555, 1566, "DATE"]]}
{"text": "KUALA LUMPUR: The Youth, Wanita and Puteri wings of Umno were in combative mood, with their leaders striking hard at their Opposition counterparts. Wanita chief Datuk Seri Shahrizat Abdul Jalil expressed surprise that her PKR rival Zuraida Kamaruddin “had the audacity” to demand her resignation over the National Feedlot Corporation controversy. She dared Zuraida to ask her party president Datuk Seri Wan Azizah Ismail to step down because her husband, Opposition Leader Datuk Seri Anwar Ibrahim, “had been found guilty and charged with various offences which I don't even have the heart to say out loud”. This, said Shahrizat, would be in accordance with Zuraida's logic behind blaming a person for the actions of his or her spouse. For his part, Umno Youth chief Khairy Jamaluddin mocked his PKR nemesis, Shamsul Iskandar Mohd Akin, for suggesting that Umno change the Federal Constitution so that only a Malay can be Prime Minister. He said PKR suggested such a proposal only because it realised that its support among the Malays was waning. Puteri Umno chief Datuk Rosnah Rashid Shirlin, meanwhile, slammed the Opposition for “twisting facts and figures” to arouse fear among the people over the country's economic situation. For his part, Umno Youth chief Khairy Jamaluddin mocked his PKR nemesis, Shamsul Iskandar Mohd Akin, for suggesting that Umno change the Federal Constitution so that only a Malay can be Prime Minister. He said PKR suggested such a proposal only because it realised that its support among the Malays was waning. Puteri Umno chief Datuk Rosnah Rashid Shirlin, meanwhile, slammed the Opposition for “twisting facts and figures” to arouse fear among the people over the country's economic situation.", "labels": [[0, 5, "ORG"], [18, 23, "PERSON"], [25, 31, "PERSON"], [36, 42, "ORG"], [52, 56, "ORG"], [123, 133, "ORG"], [148, 154, "PERSON"], [161, 171, "PERSON"], [172, 193, "PERSON"], [222, 225, "ORG"], [232, 250, "PERSON"], [301, 333, "ORG"], [357, 364, "NORP"], [392, 406, "PERSON"], [407, 420, "PERSON"], [473, 497, "PERSON"], [619, 628, "PERSON"], [658, 665, "PERSON"], [750, 760, "PERSON"], [767, 784, "PERSON"], [796, 799, "ORG"], [809, 835, "PERSON"], [869, 893, "LAW"], [909, 914, "NORP"], [946, 949, "ORG"], [1028, 1034, "DATE"], [1047, 1058, "ORG"], [1065, 1092, "PERSON"], [1117, 1127, "ORG"], [1246, 1256, "PERSON"], [1263, 1280, "PERSON"], [1292, 1295, "ORG"], [1305, 1331, "PERSON"], [1365, 1389, "LAW"], [1405, 1410, "NORP"], [1442, 1445, "ORG"], [1524, 1530, "DATE"], [1543, 1554, "ORG"], [1561, 1588, "PERSON"], [1613, 1623, "ORG"]]}
{"text": "PUTRAJAYA: The legalisation and amnesty process under the 6P programme for illegal foreign workers will be carried out simultaneously to enable those wishing to return to their countries to do so immediately. The amnesty process involved two categories those who had participated in the registration process and wished to leave the country and those who had surrendered voluntarily. Home Minister Datuk Seri Hishammuddin Hussein said under the process, the illegals could directly deal with the Immigration Department to obtain the Exit Inspection Memo without any action being taken against them. “As of Monday, a total of 25,561 illegal immigrants had been granted amnesty and had left the country. “Among the five countries that registered the most number of the illegals, who had been granted amnesty and had left, were Indonesia with 15,901 immigrants, followed by India (2,501), Nepal (1,048), Myanmar (1,040) and Vietnam (930),” he said in a statement yesterday. The 6P programme comprises registration, legalisation, amnesty, supervision, enforcement and deportation. Hishammuddin said they had been screened and were found free of any criminal record. “They have returned home with all costs fully borne by themselves,” he said, adding that the Government had not allocated any money to finance costs including food and temporary lodging. Hishammuddin added that under the programme, the Government saved about RM3.3bil in gross expenditure to register 1,303,126 illegal immigrants, which ended on Aug 31. He said the Government had instead managed to increase collection from fees charged for the levy, pass and visa imposed on foreign workers who were legalised. He said that as of Sunday, 27,514 illegal immigrants had been legalised involving 2,208 employers.", "labels": [[0, 9, "ORG"], [238, 241, "CARDINAL"], [397, 428, "PERSON"], [491, 517, "ORG"], [528, 552, "FAC"], [605, 611, "DATE"], [624, 630, "CARDINAL"], [712, 716, "CARDINAL"], [824, 833, "GPE"], [839, 845, "CARDINAL"], [870, 875, "GPE"], [877, 882, "CARDINAL"], [885, 890, "GPE"], [892, 897, "CARDINAL"], [900, 907, "GPE"], [909, 914, "CARDINAL"], [920, 927, "GPE"], [929, 932, "CARDINAL"], [959, 968, "DATE"], [1076, 1088, "PERSON"], [1254, 1264, "ORG"], [1348, 1360, "PERSON"], [1397, 1407, "ORG"], [1462, 1471, "CARDINAL"], [1507, 1513, "DATE"], [1527, 1537, "ORG"], [1693, 1699, "DATE"], [1701, 1707, "CARDINAL"], [1756, 1761, "CARDINAL"]]}
{"text": "SHAH ALAM: The defence in the High Court murder trial of cosmetics millionaire Datuk Sosilawati Lawiya and three others Thursday submitted an application to cite the prosecution for contempt of court. Lawyer Manjeet Singh Dhillon made the application against deputy public prosecutors Idham Abd Ghani and Saiful Edris Zainuddin, following their case against key prosecution witness U. Suresh for perjury, at the Sessions Court here Wednesday. Manjeet Singh, counsel for former lawyer N. Pathmanaban, the first accused in the murder case, said the charge against Suresh should not have been made since the trial was still on and the presiding judge, Datuk Akhtar Tahir, had yet to make his decision on whether to impeach the witness. However, Saiful Edris said the prosecution had the right to do so as Suresh was their witness. Akhtar set Monday to hear submissions from both parties. On Wednesday, Suresh pleaded not guilty and claimed trial to a charge of giving false evidence during the proceedings of Public Prosecutor vs Pathmanabhan, T. Thilaiyalagan, R. Matan and R. Khatavarayan before Judge Datuk Akhtar Tahir, contradicting his statement to recording officer ASP Ong Seng Keong on Oct 26 2010 in Sungai Udang Prison, Malacca. The offence was allegedly committed between 9.30am and 12 noon on July 25 and 27 in High Court 8 here. Suresh is the 29th prosecution witness in the trial of Pathmanabhan, 42, Thilaiyagan, 20; Matan, 21, and Khatavarayan, 31, who are charged with murdering Sosilawati, 47; lawyer Ahmad Kamil Abdul Karim, 32; bank officer Noorhisham Mohamad, 38; and Sosilawati's driver, Kamaruddin Shamsuddin, 44, at Lot 2001, Jalan Tanjong Layang, Tanjung Sepat, Banting, between 8.30pm and 9.45pm on Aug 30, 2010. - Bernama", "labels": [[30, 40, "ORG"], [79, 102, "ORG"], [107, 112, "CARDINAL"], [120, 128, "DATE"], [208, 229, "PERSON"], [285, 300, "PERSON"], [312, 327, "PERSON"], [382, 391, "PERSON"], [408, 426, "ORG"], [432, 441, "DATE"], [443, 456, "PERSON"], [484, 498, "PERSON"], [504, 509, "ORDINAL"], [562, 568, "PERSON"], [649, 667, "PERSON"], [742, 754, "PERSON"], [802, 808, "PERSON"], [828, 834, "ORG"], [839, 845, "DATE"], [888, 897, "DATE"], [899, 905, "ORG"], [1006, 1023, "ORG"], [1041, 1057, "PERSON"], [1059, 1067, "PERSON"], [1072, 1087, "PERSON"], [1101, 1113, "PERSON"], [1114, 1119, "PERSON"], [1170, 1173, "ORG"], [1192, 1203, "DATE"], [1228, 1235, "PERSON"], [1292, 1299, "TIME"], [1303, 1310, "DATE"], [1321, 1331, "FAC"], [1332, 1338, "TIME"], [1354, 1358, "ORDINAL"], [1395, 1407, "GPE"], [1409, 1411, "DATE"], [1413, 1424, "GPE"], [1426, 1428, "CARDINAL"], [1430, 1435, "GPE"], [1437, 1439, "DATE"], [1445, 1457, "GPE"], [1459, 1461, "DATE"], [1494, 1504, "GPE"], [1506, 1508, "CARDINAL"], [1517, 1540, "PERSON"], [1542, 1544, "DATE"], [1559, 1577, "PERSON"], [1579, 1581, "DATE"], [1587, 1597, "GPE"], [1608, 1629, "PERSON"], [1631, 1633, "DATE"], [1638, 1646, "DATE"], [1648, 1668, "PERSON"], [1670, 1683, "GPE"], [1685, 1692, "GPE"], [1713, 1719, "CARDINAL"], [1723, 1735, "DATE"]]}
{"text": "SEREMBAN: The Government should institute disciplinary and legal action against MACC officers who had failed to observe procedures which led to the death of political aide Teoh Beng Hock. MCA president Datuk Seri Dr Chua Soi Lek said it was obvious that some MACC personnel had adopted an indifferent attitude in interrogating Teoh. “They were arrogant, abusive, lacked discipline and interpersonal skills,” he said after attending a dialogue session with members of non-governmental organisations here last night. Dr Chua said the MACC should also review its interrogation procedures. He also expressed his sympathy to Teoh's family, adding that the MCA respected the findings by the RCI. “We understand what they have and are going through,” he said. DAP adviser Lim Kit Siang called for the suspension of the officers for their aggressive questioning. The MACC officers must be charged, he said, while questioning whether Teoh's death was caused by suicide or forced suicide. Transparency International Malaysia president Datuk Paul Low said the findings of the RCI must be trusted because it was properly constituted and its members were people of integrity. Related Stories: Teoh driven to suicide; MACC trio singled out over intensive grilling' The last straw for Teoh Report: Officers lied in the spirit of brotherhood Interrogators known for their brutal methods Shortcomings found in payment procedures Teoh's family rejects findings; mum adamant he was murdered Nazri: Govt expresses regret and hopes for closure I don't believe it was suicide, says Teoh's boss MACC accepts RCI findings Proposal to curb powers under MACC Act RCI states ways to improve commission *Full report of RCI findings", "labels": [[14, 24, "ORG"], [80, 84, "ORG"], [172, 186, "PERSON"], [188, 191, "ORG"], [202, 212, "PERSON"], [216, 228, "PERSON"], [259, 263, "ORG"], [327, 331, "PERSON"], [503, 513, "TIME"], [532, 536, "ORG"], [620, 624, "PERSON"], [651, 654, "ORG"], [685, 688, "ORG"], [753, 756, "ORG"], [765, 778, "PERSON"], [859, 863, "ORG"], [925, 929, "PERSON"], [979, 1014, "ORG"], [1025, 1039, "PERSON"], [1065, 1068, "ORG"], [1180, 1184, "PERSON"], [1204, 1208, "ORG"], [1270, 1281, "WORK_OF_ART"], [1371, 1383, "ORG"], [1412, 1416, "PERSON"], [1472, 1477, "PERSON"], [1479, 1483, "PERSON"], [1560, 1564, "PERSON"], [1572, 1576, "ORG"], [1585, 1588, "ORG"], [1628, 1636, "LAW"], [1637, 1640, "ORG"], [1691, 1694, "ORG"]]}
{"text": "SERI KEMBANGAN: Thirty-nine cases of illegal sales of subsidised domestic liquefied petroleum gas (LPG) have been detected nationwide. Deputy Domestic Trade, Cooperatives and Consumerism Minister Datuk Tan Lian Hoe said the ministry's enforcement officers had seized 56,750kg of LPG worth RM332,634.85 from January. She added that the syndicates would siphon the gas from 12kg or 14kg LPG cylinders meant for domestic consumption and transfer it to 50kg cylinders for resale. “LPG is highly flammable and the transferring of gas is very dangerous and can spark an explosion. “Stern action will be taken against unscrupulous operators. They can be charged under Control of Supplies Act 1961,” she said at Shell Malaysia's Home Safety Awareness Campaign 2011 at Aeon Taman Equine shopping centre here yesterday. Tan said the price of a 14kg LPG cylinder was RM49.42, of which RM22.82 of the amount is subsidised by the government. “This means the public only have to pay RM26.60 per cylinder,” she added. In her speech, Tan urged the public to buy their LPG tanks from licensed distributors who adhered to regulations set by the Fire and Rescue Department. She added that the ministry had issued 5,398 retail licences to distribute LPG nationwide. Tan said the licences should be displayed by the sellers at their premises and the public could call the ministry to check on them. The Home Safety Awareness Campaign includes a roadshow that will run for 12 weekends at 12 locations in Peninsular Malaysia. Free brochures and videos on the “Safe Handling of Shell LPG” will be distributed during the roadshows and can be downloaded at www.shell.com.my.", "labels": [[0, 4, "ORG"], [16, 27, "CARDINAL"], [142, 156, "ORG"], [158, 170, "ORG"], [196, 214, "PERSON"], [267, 275, "QUANTITY"], [289, 301, "CARDINAL"], [307, 314, "DATE"], [372, 376, "QUANTITY"], [380, 388, "QUANTITY"], [449, 453, "QUANTITY"], [661, 689, "LAW"], [704, 720, "ORG"], [721, 756, "ORG"], [760, 777, "ORG"], [799, 808, "DATE"], [810, 813, "PERSON"], [834, 838, "QUANTITY"], [1018, 1021, "PERSON"], [1052, 1055, "ORG"], [1123, 1153, "ORG"], [1194, 1199, "CARDINAL"], [1230, 1233, "ORG"], [1246, 1249, "PERSON"], [1378, 1412, "ORG"], [1451, 1453, "CARDINAL"], [1466, 1468, "CARDINAL"], [1482, 1501, "LOC"], [1537, 1563, "WORK_OF_ART"]]}
{"text": "TOKYO: The chief of the 10-member Association of Southeast Asian Nations (Asean) called for a candidate for the post of managing director of the International Monetary Fund from outside Europe or North America. Asean Secretary General Surin Pitsuwan, in a seminar here, told Kyodo News that a few candidates could also be found in Asia. This region must be given opportunity to make a contribution in the governance of those global institutions important to all of us, he said. He added that there are individuals who were capable of assuming the top post at the Washington-based IMF in countries such as Indonesia, Singapore and Mexico, and it is necessary to field a candidate from Europe or North America, even if the chances appear slim that the post would be secured this time. As a secretary general of Asean, I would say just go for it, and even if we do not win this time, we should not let it go without a challenge as this post is not monopoly of Europe, he said. On Wednesday, French Finance Minister Christine Lagarde announced her bid to become head of the IMF and succeed her compatriot Dominique Strauss-Kahn who resigned after being charged with sexual assault in New York earlier this month. Lagarde is seen as the front-runner in the race to become managing director of the IMF as she is supported by major European countries such as Britain and Germany. The fund, which began accepting candidacies for its top position on Monday, aims to complete the selection process by the end of June. - Bernama", "labels": [[20, 79, "ORG"], [141, 172, "ORG"], [186, 192, "LOC"], [196, 209, "LOC"], [211, 216, "NORP"], [235, 249, "PERSON"], [275, 285, "ORG"], [331, 335, "LOC"], [567, 577, "GPE"], [609, 618, "GPE"], [620, 629, "GPE"], [634, 640, "GPE"], [688, 694, "LOC"], [698, 711, "LOC"], [815, 820, "NORP"], [963, 969, "LOC"], [985, 994, "DATE"], [996, 1002, "NORP"], [1020, 1037, "PERSON"], [1109, 1131, "PERSON"], [1188, 1196, "GPE"], [1197, 1215, "DATE"], [1217, 1224, "DATE"], [1333, 1341, "NORP"], [1360, 1367, "GPE"], [1372, 1379, "GPE"], [1449, 1455, "DATE"], [1499, 1514, "DATE"]]}
{"text": "PUTRAJAYA: Some parents have welcomed the punishment for National Service (NS) dodgers describing it as probably the best way to discipline the young. They also have no qualm about the requirement for the dodgers to attend NS training after completing their punishment. Accountant Muhamad Abu Zarin said the punishment, in the form of carrying out community service, was to educate young Malaysians about being disciplined. “We need disciplined young Malaysians if we are to become a developed nation and since NS has been made compulsory, those who try to escape should know the consequences. “Since there is a law to punish the dodgers, enforce it for the good of the nation,” he said yesterday. However, Muhamad, whose eldest child is aged 20 but has yet to be called for the training, wanted the NS Department to be serious about enforcing the law. NS Department director-general Datuk Abdul Hadi Awang Kechil had said on Friday that dodgers who were eventually charged in court would have to do community service as punishment. He said they would also be compelled to do national training once they completed the punishment. The D-G explained that under the National Service Training Act 2003, the department could summon anyone below the age of 35 to attend training. Another father, A. Rajendran, said the department needed to be more serious about punishing dodgers. He said although the training scheme started in 2004 and 500 youths had not attended it, no action was taken against the dodgers. “Seven years down the road and the 500 dodgers are still not being punished,” he said.", "labels": [[0, 9, "ORG"], [57, 73, "ORG"], [75, 77, "ORG"], [223, 225, "ORG"], [281, 298, "PERSON"], [388, 398, "NORP"], [451, 461, "NORP"], [511, 513, "ORG"], [687, 696, "DATE"], [707, 714, "ORG"], [743, 745, "CARDINAL"], [796, 813, "ORG"], [853, 866, "ORG"], [884, 913, "PERSON"], [926, 932, "DATE"], [1159, 1197, "LAW"], [1240, 1253, "DATE"], [1290, 1302, "PERSON"], [1423, 1427, "DATE"], [1432, 1435, "CARDINAL"], [1506, 1517, "DATE"], [1540, 1543, "CARDINAL"]]}
{"text": "MARANG: Eight secondary schoolboys trespassed into another school and beat up one of its students because the victim is a top student in his school. The schoolboys, who were from a nearby school, were said to have been asked by the victim's schoolmate to beat him up. The instigator was believed to have been envious of the academic achievements of SMK Agama Durian Guling student Wan Nur Azri Wan Mohammad. The eight ended up in the magistrate's court yesterday where they were charged with trespassing into another school as well as beating up the Form Five student. The boys, comprising four Form Five students, three Form Three students and a Form Four student, pleaded guilty to trespassing into Wan Nur Azri's school between 11am and 11.30am on April 7. The offence under Section 447 of the Penal Code carries a RM3,000 fine or six months' jail. They also admitted causing multiple injuries to Wan Nur Azri. They can be jailed up to a year or fined RM2,000 or both under Section 323. According to the facts of the case, Wan Nur Azri was chatting with his friends in the classroom when the eight rushed in. The teacher was not in at that time. He was dragged out and pushed behind a chemistry lab before being assaulted by the group. His classmates rushed out to inform a teacher, who managed to stop the assault. The eight boys then fled. Magistrate Nor Azizah Yusof set May 24 for the submission of a morality report and sentencing. She fixed bail at RM1,500 for each accused. Insp Mahathir Mohd Yusof prosecuted while the eight accused were not represented.", "labels": [[8, 13, "CARDINAL"], [78, 81, "CARDINAL"], [353, 358, "GPE"], [381, 406, "PERSON"], [412, 417, "CARDINAL"], [453, 462, "DATE"], [590, 594, "CARDINAL"], [615, 620, "CARDINAL"], [626, 631, "CARDINAL"], [652, 656, "CARDINAL"], [701, 715, "PERSON"], [751, 758, "DATE"], [778, 789, "LAW"], [793, 807, "LAW"], [818, 825, "PRODUCT"], [834, 845, "DATE"], [900, 912, "PERSON"], [933, 945, "DATE"], [955, 962, "CARDINAL"], [977, 988, "LAW"], [1026, 1038, "PERSON"], [1095, 1100, "CARDINAL"], [1323, 1328, "CARDINAL"], [1360, 1372, "PERSON"], [1377, 1383, "DATE"], [1458, 1465, "ORG"], [1484, 1508, "PERSON"], [1530, 1535, "CARDINAL"]]}
{"text": "KUALA LUMPUR: The Agosta submarine, which had been used to train Royal Malaysian Navy personnel in France, will arrive here in August. Navy Chief Adm Tan Sri Abdul Aziz Jaafar said the submarine, which has been decommissioned, would become a museum piece. “We are expecting its arrival in August. There will be a signing ceremony between the Defence Ministry secretary-general and the French side before it is handed over to us,” he told a press conference here yesterday. On the country's first two submarines KD Tunku Abdul Rahman and KD Tun Razak Adm Abdul Aziz said they were in the open sea and operating smoothly, contrary to reports. He also denied claims that kickbacks were involved over the two Scorpene submarines, adding that neither the European Union nor the RMN condoned such acts. It was announced last month that the submarines would cost RM50mil a year to maintain. On the pirate-infested Gulf of Aden, Adm Abdul Aziz said there could be two RMN auxiliary escort ships guarding Malaysian trading vessels by the end of this year. The second ship, he said, would supplement Bunga Mas 5, which successfully foiled a hijacking attempt against Malaysian MT Bunga Laurel last January. Commandos had captured seven Somali pirates who have since been charged here. Adm Abdul Aziz said assigning Bunga Mas 6 as the second auxiliary ship resulted from continued strategic cooperation between the RMN and the Malaysian International Shipping Corporation (MISC). He also said that NGV Tech Sdn Bhd would build two training ships for the RMN at its shipyard in Sijangkang, Selangor with a two-year completion target.", "labels": [[0, 5, "ORG"], [18, 24, "NORP"], [65, 85, "ORG"], [99, 105, "GPE"], [127, 133, "DATE"], [135, 139, "ORG"], [146, 175, "PERSON"], [289, 295, "DATE"], [342, 358, "ORG"], [385, 391, "NORP"], [462, 471, "DATE"], [490, 495, "ORDINAL"], [496, 499, "CARDINAL"], [520, 532, "PERSON"], [537, 539, "ORG"], [540, 564, "PERSON"], [701, 704, "CARDINAL"], [746, 764, "ORG"], [773, 776, "ORG"], [814, 824, "DATE"], [907, 919, "LOC"], [921, 935, "PERSON"], [956, 959, "CARDINAL"], [960, 963, "ORG"], [996, 1005, "NORP"], [1025, 1045, "DATE"], [1051, 1057, "ORDINAL"], [1090, 1099, "ORG"], [1157, 1182, "ORG"], [1183, 1195, "DATE"], [1220, 1225, "CARDINAL"], [1226, 1232, "NORP"], [1275, 1289, "PERSON"], [1305, 1314, "ORG"], [1324, 1330, "ORDINAL"], [1404, 1407, "ORG"], [1412, 1460, "ORG"], [1487, 1503, "ORG"], [1516, 1519, "CARDINAL"], [1543, 1546, "ORG"], [1566, 1576, "GPE"], [1578, 1586, "PERSON"], [1594, 1602, "DATE"]]}
{"text": "PORT DICKSON: The government will from this year conduct the national health and morbidity study once in four years instead of once in 10 years as previously done, said Health Minister Datuk Seri Liow Tiong Lai. He said the move was aimed at improving healthcare policies and the living standards of the people. He added that 10,000 households involving some 40,000 respondents were selected for a three-month exercise this year and expressed hope that they would extend their fullest cooperation to the authorities. “We have decided to shorten the study as we want to have a more accurate picture on the lifestyle, eating habits, health patterns and what Malaysians spend on healthcare. “We need this information as we want to ensure every Malaysian has access to healthcare services. We want to transform and restructure our health services for the peoples’ benefit,” he said at the launch of the 4th National Health and Morbidity Study 2011-2014 at a resort here yesterday. Liow said data from the study will, among others, be used to formulate the “1Care for 1Malaysia” policy as well as the National Strategic Plan for Non-Communicable Diseases. The ministry has trained 400 staff to conduct the study which would be carried out from April 18. The respondents were randomly selected by the Statistics Department. He said the staff would collect data on smoking habits and alcohol consumption among Malaysians and if they suffered from diabetes, hypertension, cardiovascular diseases, high cholesterol levels and obesity. The respondents will be referred to government clinics or hospitals if they needed treatment and will not be charged any fee.", "labels": [[39, 48, "DATE"], [105, 115, "DATE"], [135, 143, "DATE"], [185, 200, "PERSON"], [201, 210, "PERSON"], [326, 332, "CARDINAL"], [354, 365, "CARDINAL"], [398, 409, "DATE"], [419, 428, "DATE"], [656, 666, "NORP"], [741, 750, "NORP"], [899, 902, "ORDINAL"], [903, 948, "EVENT"], [966, 975, "DATE"], [977, 981, "PERSON"], [1048, 1058, "DATE"], [1063, 1072, "CARDINAL"], [1176, 1179, "CARDINAL"], [1239, 1247, "DATE"], [1291, 1316, "ORG"], [1403, 1413, "NORP"]]}
{"text": "SEPANG: It is all systems go for tomorrow's 2011 Formula One Petronas Malaysia Grand Prix and while there seem to be fewer promotions this year, Sepang International Circuit (SIC) chairman Datuk Mokhzani Mahathir begs to differ. While other circuits like Singapore focus more on concerts, Malaysia, he said, was doing things “slightly differently” by emphasising on the race itself. Mokhzani said SIC was also giving more opportunities to the private sector and teams to organise their events this year such as street demonstrations by Team Lotus and Red Bull Racing. “Funding has to come from the private sector,” he said, adding that the circuit was ready to host the race with, among others, a free pit walkabout for schoolchildren yesterday and a free concert by Korean artiste Rain tomorrow. Instead of hosting the annual gala dinner, Prime Minister Datuk Seri Najib Tun Razak met Formula One team principals and drivers along with invited guests at Sri Perdana in Putrajaya on Thursday night. “It is a networking opportunity for the corporate sector, Formula One and the Government,” Mokhzani said. He pointed out that while Singapore had had artistes such as Beyonce and Mariah Carey perform in the past, they were “standalone” concerts which fans paid for separately compared to the free ones SIC hosted for grandstand ticket holders in Malaysia. “We do have quality acts. Some may not find Rain exciting but he is putting on a complete show and not just standing there and singing,” he said, adding that ticket prices in the island republic were higher and the government charged a levy on hotels in the F1 circuit area.", "labels": [[33, 48, "DATE"], [134, 143, "DATE"], [145, 173, "ORG"], [175, 178, "ORG"], [189, 212, "PERSON"], [255, 264, "GPE"], [289, 297, "GPE"], [383, 391, "PERSON"], [397, 400, "ORG"], [493, 502, "DATE"], [536, 546, "ORG"], [551, 566, "ORG"], [735, 744, "DATE"], [767, 773, "NORP"], [782, 786, "PERSON"], [787, 795, "DATE"], [820, 826, "DATE"], [855, 881, "PERSON"], [886, 893, "PERSON"], [955, 966, "FAC"], [970, 979, "GPE"], [983, 997, "TIME"], [1057, 1068, "PERSON"], [1077, 1087, "ORG"], [1090, 1098, "PERSON"], [1131, 1140, "GPE"], [1166, 1173, "PERSON"], [1178, 1190, "PERSON"], [1301, 1304, "ORG"], [1345, 1353, "GPE"]]}
{"text": "When the Finance Minister tabled Budget 2013 and reduced personal income tax rate by 1%, some quarters have asked if this brings us one step closer to the GST. EVER grumbled about having to pay the RM50 government tax for your credit card each year? Well, the good news is there will be no more such tax if the proposed GST (goods and services tax) is implemented. And you will pay GST on the credit card only if your bank charges you for the card. “These days, banks are offering credits cards for free and giving waivers on annual subscription. If the card is free, there will be no GST on it,” says Customs Department director-general Datuk Khazali Ahmad in an interview. He stresses that key sectors like the financial services, public transport, healthcare, education and residential housing will be exempt from GST. This essentially means that education, medical care, bus and train tickets as well as highway tolls will still be just as affordable as today. Thus, the lower income groups will not be burdened by the GST. When it comes to insurance, Khazali says, if it is a life policy (including education, investment-linked and endowment), no GST will be imposed. But if it is a general insurance policy for medical, fire, motor, burglary, then the normal GST rate (proposed at 4%) will apply. Despite the GST being a fairer, more effective and transparent taxation system and one that has been successfully implemented in 146 countries, it has not been easy to push the idea through in Malaysia. In fact, the government has been talking about the GST for more than two decades now (even when Datuk Seri Anwar Ibrahim was the Finance Minister in the 1990s). In December 2009, the GST bill was tabled in parliament for first reading but it was withdrawn on April 19 this year for amendments. The Finance Ministry on its website has asked the public for views and feedback on the proposed GST. With public awareness still very low on how GST works, it might be years before it actually comes to fruition. People are still not aware that their basic needs will be protected under the proposed GST regime because essential food items like rice, meat, fish, seafood, chicken, vegetables, cooking oil and salt will be “zero-rated”, which means there will no GST imposed. Critical services like schools, financial services, hospitals, roads and public transport will be “GST-exempt”, which means the consumer will be exempted from paying GST on them. And if you buy a flight ticket to a destination abroad, you will not have to pay GST. “You will be charged GST only on goods and services (which are not zero or exempt-rated) that you consume in the country what you consume outside the country will not be subject to a local GST. A flight ticket abroad and overseas travel is consumption outside Malaysia, so you don't pay GST here on it,” says Khazali. The GST is a consumption-based tax where the tax is borne by the person who consumes the goods or services. Ultimately, it should reduce business costs because manufacturers, distributors and suppliers are able to claim back the GST they paid on goods and services acquired for the purpose of their business. And these businesses are supposed to pass those savings down to the consumer, which should result in lower prices. Khazali says people find it hard to accept the GST even though it benefits them because “tax” is never a popular subject. “Generally, nobody likes to be taxed or, rather, the word “tax” is taboo to many. “However, governments all over the world need to impose tax to get the revenue to provide their citizens with their social needs, employment, security and so forth.” Educating consumers on the GST, he admits, is not easy because the moment you say that GST is a form of tax, “you will be faced with a wall of resistance”. “So we have to explain the GST and its benefits to the people continuously to avoid or eliminate whatever misconception they have about it,” he adds. Khazali also notes that most people do not know that the GST actually replaces the current sales and services tax which they have already been paying on a lot of goods and services because it is embedded in the price of what they buy. Under the current system, by the time the goods reach the consumers, the sales tax that is paid at the manufacturers level would have cascaded at each level of the distribution and the supply chain, and this results in a higher price. But with the GST, since businesses at every stage are able to get a refund on the GST paid on the goods and services acquired or used for the purpose of their business, this will eliminate the cascading effect suffered under the current sales and services taxes. And because of this, an immediate reduction in prices should be seen for goods and services where people have all along been paying an embedded sales tax. He also stresses that the government has repeatedly emphasised that the people will have to understand the GST first before the government actually implements it. “The public should not have any fear over GST. It is a form of consumption tax which has been implemented in nearly 150 countries in the world, whether developed or developing, so there must be something good about it. “ He says the GST is also supposed to result in cheaper prices for imported goods. At present, unless exempted, imported goods are subject to an import duty and sales tax. With the GST replacing the sales tax (5% to 10%), imported goods will still be subject to an import duty and a GST; but because the proposed GST rate is lower than the existing sales tax, consumers should be paying less. Before implementing the GST too, he says, the government will also educate businesses on the need to pass down the savings they get from the GST refund, and set up a mechanism to stop businesses from trying to profiteer from it. For him, the GST is a good thing because it will reduce business costs, lead to more competitive pricing, make exports more competitive because exports will be zero-rated (meaning no GST), increase gross domestic production and reduce grey economy activities. Khazali also believes there might be a change in consumption pattern with the GST because the GST works on the affordability concept. “Consumers have to decide which goods or services to buy. They pay GST only when the goods or services are consumed. So they may divert more of their expenses towards essential goods and services rather than on luxury goods.” Khazali also points out that if the GST is implemented here at the proposed rate of 4%, it will be the lowest rate in the region. Indonesia, Thailand, Cambodia, Vietnam and Laos charge a 10% GST rate, Philippines 12% and Singapore 7%. But what is to stop the government from hiking the rate after it has been implemented? Khazali cites past experiences, saying Malaysia increased its sales tax rate only once from 5% in 1972 (year of implementation) to 10% in 1983 and service tax rate too increased only once, from 5% in 1975 (year of implementation) to 6% in 2011. There are still nuts and bolts to sort out with implementing the GST here, including tabling a new bill for it, putting an anti-profiteering mechanism in place, getting public understanding and acceptance on it. For now, it looks like it is still quite a long journey away.", "labels": [[85, 87, "PERCENT"], [89, 102, "CARDINAL"], [132, 135, "CARDINAL"], [155, 158, "ORG"], [160, 164, "ORG"], [239, 248, "DATE"], [320, 323, "ORG"], [382, 385, "ORG"], [602, 620, "ORG"], [638, 657, "PERSON"], [817, 820, "ORG"], [958, 963, "DATE"], [1023, 1026, "ORG"], [1056, 1063, "PERSON"], [1287, 1289, "PERCENT"], [1315, 1318, "ORG"], [1432, 1435, "CARDINAL"], [1496, 1504, "GPE"], [1557, 1560, "ORG"], [1565, 1586, "DATE"], [1602, 1626, "PERSON"], [1655, 1664, "DATE"], [1670, 1683, "DATE"], [1689, 1692, "ORG"], [1727, 1732, "ORDINAL"], [1765, 1783, "DATE"], [1800, 1820, "ORG"], [1945, 1948, "ORG"], [1968, 1973, "DATE"], [2099, 2102, "ORG"], [2222, 2226, "CARDINAL"], [2606, 2610, "CARDINAL"], [2728, 2731, "ORG"], [2799, 2807, "GPE"], [2848, 2855, "PERSON"], [2861, 2864, "ORG"], [3086, 3089, "ORG"], [3281, 3288, "PERSON"], [3328, 3331, "ORG"], [3678, 3681, "ORG"], [3738, 3741, "ORG"], [3834, 3837, "ORG"], [3957, 3964, "PERSON"], [4014, 4017, "ORG"], [4440, 4443, "ORG"], [4509, 4512, "ORG"], [4952, 4955, "ORG"], [5050, 5053, "ORG"], [5117, 5127, "CARDINAL"], [5241, 5244, "ORG"], [5408, 5411, "ORG"], [5437, 5446, "PERCENT"], [5510, 5513, "ORG"], [5644, 5647, "ORG"], [5761, 5764, "ORG"], [5862, 5865, "ORG"], [6009, 6013, "CARDINAL"], [6109, 6116, "PERSON"], [6187, 6190, "ORG"], [6203, 6206, "ORG"], [6469, 6476, "PERSON"], [6505, 6508, "ORG"], [6553, 6555, "PERCENT"], [6599, 6608, "GPE"], [6610, 6618, "GPE"], [6620, 6628, "GPE"], [6630, 6637, "GPE"], [6642, 6646, "GPE"], [6656, 6659, "PERCENT"], [6670, 6681, "GPE"], [6682, 6685, "PERCENT"], [6690, 6699, "GPE"], [6700, 6702, "PERCENT"], [6791, 6798, "PERSON"], [6830, 6838, "GPE"], [6883, 6885, "PERCENT"], [6889, 6893, "DATE"], [6922, 6925, "PERCENT"], [6929, 6933, "DATE"], [6985, 6987, "PERCENT"], [6991, 6995, "DATE"], [7024, 7026, "PERCENT"], [7030, 7034, "DATE"], [7101, 7104, "ORG"]]}
{"text": "WSJ reported on July 3 that US$700 million may have moved through agencies linked to debt-ridden 1MDB and ended up in Malaysia’s Prime Minister Najib Razak's accounts. Najib says he has not taken money for personal gain. — Reuters pic HONG KONG, July 21 — Malaysia Prime Minister Datuk Seri Najib Razak’s biggest source of support—his own party—could also be the most realistic threat to his leadership. As the premier faces an investigation sparked by a Wall Street Journal report that US$700 million (RM2.6 billion) may have wended its way into his personal bank accounts, the ruling coalition has swiftly closed ranks around him. The probe has sparked a raid on the state investment company whose advisory board Najib chairs, and spurred calls to resign from opposition lawmakers and even former premier Tun Mahathir Mohamad. But Najib continues his grip on power with the help of his United Malays National Organisation (Umno), which leads an alliance and has governed Malaysia since 1957. Part of Najib’s staying power reflects a lack of external threats with the opposition bloc recently collapsing amid internal bickering. There are few signs of public discontent over the money trail claims. Internally Najib’s built a support network since coming to power in 2009 that ranges from government ministers to party division heads. He’s rallied rank and file members with a variety of pro-Malay policies in the past 18 months. Najib doubles as finance minister and is also the party chief. The biggest risk would be if party chiefs at some point decide he’s become a potential liability to lead them into the next election, due to be held by 2018, especially as the coalition lost the popular vote for the first time in 2013 as non-Malay voters deserted it. ‘Pockets of dissatisfaction’ “If you are asking me whether there are pockets of dissatisfaction within the party, then the honest answer is of course there is,” said Syed Ali Alhabshee, an Umno division chief in Kuala Lumpur. “But is there a serious division within Umno, which is threatening to split the party? Of course not.” Ibrahim Suffian, an analyst at the Merdeka Center for Opinion Research, said Umno’s chiefs may only move against Najib if discontent spills onto the streets. “Umno division and branch leaders will have to see real public unhappiness with policies before they act,” he said. The Journal reported July 3 that US$700 million may have moved through agencies linked to debt-ridden 1Malaysia Development Bhd. and ended up in Najib’s accounts. Najib says he has not taken money for personal gain. Audit report Controversy over 1MDB’s finances has dogged Najib for months, though an initial audit report this month didn’t reveal any suspicious activity. The probes of 1MDB are now intersecting with the investigation into Najib. “All these accusations against Najib, whether it is by the opposition, by Mahathir and by the foreign media, they are accusations against the party,” said Shahrir Samad, a lawmaker and Umno division leader for Johor Bahru in southern Malaysia. “Everyone is united, defending the party.” Najib’s office didn’t respond to requests for comment. Najib told Malaysians in a July 16 speech to be wary of internal and external threats, including interference from foreign powers that may undermine the country’s stability and sovereignty. There are issues chipping away at the premier’s popularity. Economic growth is slowing and he’s still working to bed down an unpopular goods and services tax. The most recent major opinion poll conducted in January showed his approval rating at 44 per cent from 48 per cent in October, near a record low of 42 per cent at the start of last year. Fading popularity Najib’s predecessor Tun Abdullah Ahmad Badawi stepped down in 2009 after the coalition lost its two-thirds majority in elections in 2008 — the worst performance since 1969. His popularity within Umno had faded, fuelled in part by resignation calls from Mahathir, whose influence then resonated among party members. But Najib has more support support than Abdullah did. “Najib is entrenched in this Umno-constructed Malay state,” said Clive Kessler, an emeritus professor at the University of New South Wales who has studied Malaysian politics since 1969. “It is a fortress. He can’t be budged from there.” He’s also bought some insurance, postponing party elections scheduled for next year by 18 months. To be removed, more than half the division leaders in the party or two-thirds of the party’s decision-making body must agree to call an extraordinary meeting. At the meeting, two-thirds of those who attend would need to vote for his ouster. ‘Patronage system’ “Malaysia has a patronage system whereby the supreme leader has to take care of major honchos and so as long as he is able to satisfy their various demands and interests, they will rally around him,” said Oh Ei Sun, an analyst at the S. Rajaratnam School of International Studies in Singapore and Najib’s political secretary from 2009 to 2011. By law, donations to political parties are unlimited and parties aren’t required to report how they spend funds. Umno’s funds are highly disproportionate to other parties, according to Transparency International. The government has made greater use of the Sedition Act and a new anti-terrorism law has elements of security measures repealed in 2012. Police have investigated or charged at least 78 people for sedition since the start of 2014, according to the office of the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights. Website blocked The Sarawak Report news website was this week blocked by the Malaysian Communications and Multimedia Commission, which said its content could destabilize the country. The site responded that the action was a “blatant attempt to censor” content related to 1MDB. Najib has benefited from the implosion of the opposition bloc after the jailing of leader Anwar Ibrahim on sodomy charges Anwar said were false and politically motivated. Umno’s base is mostly ethnic Malay voters in rural areas where there is a heavy weighting of parliamentary seats. Roughly one in every 10 Malaysians are party members. Najib’s father, former premier Abdul Razak Hussein, crafted a system in the early 1970s to give preferential treatment to Malays and indigenous people, known collectively as Bumiputeras. That system endures today. Cash handouts have bolstered support among lower-income Malaysians representing about 40 per cent of the population, according to National University of Malaysia professor Shamsul Amri Baharuddin. Annual handouts will rise to 950 ringgit (US$250) from 650 ringgit, Najib said in this year’s budget. Prime Minister Datuk Seri Najib Tun Razak (left) and Deputy Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin at the Perdana Putra building in Putrajaya, July 8, 2015. — File pic Islamic credentials Umno officials are also burnishing their Islamic credentials. Some lawmakers back the efforts of the opposition PAS to introduce shariah law in a PAS-held state. While Najib enjoys the support of senior Umno officials, such as Home Minister Datuk Seri Ahmad Zahid Hamidi and Defence Minister Datuk Seri Hishammuddin Hussein, some are more circumspect. Deputy Prime Minister Tan Sri Muhyiddin Yassin has called on Najib to give a convincing explanation or denial of the money transfer allegations, while saying the investigation should be allowed to run its course. Tun Musa Hitam, deputy prime minister from 1981 to 1986 under Mahathir, has called on Najib to step aside temporarily. Some opposition figures say Najib’s support may fade as the investigations roll on. “Najib is comfortably ensconced in Umno for now,” said Lim Kit Siang, a lawmaker and leader of the Democratic Action Party. Still, “there are people who are quietly questioning what he has allegedly done and how this economy is being handled. It is too ambitious to say that he will be around until the next general elections.” — Bloomberg", "labels": [[0, 3, "ORG"], [16, 22, "DATE"], [28, 42, "MONEY"], [118, 126, "GPE"], [144, 155, "PERSON"], [168, 173, "PERSON"], [223, 230, "ORG"], [235, 244, "GPE"], [246, 253, "DATE"], [256, 264, "GPE"], [280, 304, "PERSON"], [455, 474, "ORG"], [487, 501, "MONEY"], [715, 720, "ORG"], [807, 827, "PERSON"], [833, 838, "PERSON"], [888, 929, "ORG"], [973, 981, "GPE"], [988, 992, "DATE"], [1002, 1009, "ORG"], [1200, 1218, "PERSON"], [1268, 1272, "DATE"], [1389, 1398, "NORP"], [1411, 1429, "DATE"], [1646, 1650, "DATE"], [1710, 1715, "ORDINAL"], [1724, 1728, "DATE"], [1732, 1741, "NORP"], [1928, 1946, "PERSON"], [1951, 1955, "ORG"], [1974, 1986, "GPE"], [2028, 2032, "ORG"], [2091, 2106, "PERSON"], [2122, 2140, "FAC"], [2145, 2161, "ORG"], [2168, 2172, "PERSON"], [2204, 2209, "ORG"], [2369, 2376, "ORG"], [2386, 2392, "DATE"], [2398, 2412, "MONEY"], [2510, 2515, "GPE"], [2528, 2533, "PERSON"], [2594, 2605, "ORG"], [2638, 2643, "PERSON"], [2648, 2654, "DATE"], [2687, 2697, "DATE"], [2805, 2810, "GPE"], [2843, 2848, "GPE"], [2886, 2894, "PERSON"], [2967, 2980, "PERSON"], [2997, 3001, "ORG"], [3022, 3033, "PERSON"], [3046, 3054, "GPE"], [3099, 3106, "ORG"], [3154, 3159, "PERSON"], [3165, 3175, "NORP"], [3181, 3188, "DATE"], [3551, 3558, "DATE"], [3589, 3600, "MONEY"], [3606, 3617, "MONEY"], [3621, 3628, "DATE"], [3651, 3662, "MONEY"], [3666, 3688, "DATE"], [3708, 3715, "ORG"], [3728, 3753, "PERSON"], [3770, 3774, "DATE"], [3804, 3814, "CARDINAL"], [3840, 3844, "DATE"], [3875, 3879, "DATE"], [3903, 3907, "PERSON"], [3961, 3969, "PERSON"], [4027, 4032, "PERSON"], [4063, 4071, "PERSON"], [4078, 4083, "PERSON"], [4123, 4128, "NORP"], [4142, 4155, "PERSON"], [4182, 4215, "ORG"], [4232, 4241, "NORP"], [4257, 4261, "DATE"], [4388, 4397, "DATE"], [4401, 4410, "DATE"], [4427, 4441, "CARDINAL"], [4479, 4489, "CARDINAL"], [4587, 4597, "CARDINAL"], [4673, 4681, "GPE"], [4877, 4886, "PERSON"], [4902, 4951, "ORG"], [4955, 4964, "GPE"], [4969, 4976, "ORG"], [5002, 5006, "DATE"], [5201, 5227, "ORG"], [5268, 5284, "LAW"], [5360, 5364, "DATE"], [5402, 5413, "CARDINAL"], [5490, 5504, "ORG"], [5561, 5575, "ORG"], [5593, 5602, "DATE"], [5614, 5668, "ORG"], [5818, 5823, "PERSON"], [5908, 5921, "PERSON"], [5940, 5945, "PERSON"], [6018, 6023, "NORP"], [6103, 6114, "CARDINAL"], [6124, 6126, "CARDINAL"], [6127, 6137, "NORP"], [6157, 6164, "ORG"], [6188, 6207, "PERSON"], [6229, 6244, "DATE"], [6279, 6285, "DATE"], [6331, 6342, "GPE"], [6364, 6369, "DATE"], [6427, 6437, "NORP"], [6451, 6468, "MONEY"], [6501, 6532, "ORG"], [6543, 6566, "PERSON"], [6568, 6574, "DATE"], [6597, 6600, "CARDINAL"], [6613, 6616, "MONEY"], [6623, 6626, "CARDINAL"], [6636, 6641, "PERSON"], [6655, 6659, "DATE"], [6685, 6711, "PERSON"], [6745, 6769, "PERSON"], [6777, 6790, "ORG"], [6803, 6812, "GPE"], [6814, 6826, "DATE"], [6839, 6846, "NORP"], [6859, 6863, "PERSON"], [6900, 6907, "NORP"], [6971, 6974, "ORG"], [7005, 7008, "ORG"], [7027, 7032, "PERSON"], [7062, 7066, "PRODUCT"], [7086, 7090, "ORG"], [7100, 7110, "PERSON"], [7111, 7129, "PERSON"], [7151, 7182, "PERSON"], [7233, 7257, "PERSON"], [7272, 7277, "GPE"], [7424, 7438, "PERSON"], [7467, 7471, "DATE"], [7475, 7479, "DATE"], [7486, 7494, "PERSON"], [7510, 7515, "PRODUCT"], [7571, 7578, "ORG"], [7628, 7633, "PERSON"], [7662, 7666, "PERSON"], [7682, 7695, "PERSON"], [7722, 7749, "ORG"], [7953, 7966, "PERSON"]]}
{"text": "A labourer stands next to a reactor at a pyrolysis unit in Jokhabad industrial area in the northern state of Uttar Pradesh, India May 9, 2019. — Reuters pic PASIR GUDANG, May 31 — When local investigators scoured a riverbed in southern Malaysia for clues in a chemical dumping case that hospitalised over one thousand people earlier this year, they found a cocktail of toxins, including a colourless liquid commonly secreted when tyres are recycled. That led environment officials and police to a small firm called P. Tech Resources involved in pyrolysis — a business of burning old tyres to make low-grade oil that industry sources say is also common elsewhere in South-east Asia, China and India. Police have charged a lorry driver and all three of P. Tech’s directors for violating a law prohibiting the illegal dumping of waste. The firm’s directors and the firm also each face 15 charges for offences related to waste controls and air pollution brought by the environment department. They have all denied wrongdoing. Lawyers representing them and local police declined comment citing ongoing court proceedings. Reuters was not able to reach the three directors of P. Tech or the company secretary, the only four company officials listed in documents filed with Malaysia’s companies regulator. Its premises were closed and calls to its registered office went unanswered. The documents show P. Tech, registered in 2017, manufactures and trades tyre oils. Done properly, in a controlled environment, tyre pyrolysis has been lauded by the recycling industry as a green way of turning a complex waste into a useful energy source. In this process, tyres are heated in the absence of oxygen and the gases released are condensed into a low-quality oil that can be used in asphalt or fuel oil, depending on its purity. Some firms in Europe and the United States have developed technology to limit emissions and waste from pyrolysis, but with low margins this green approach has not had widespread commercial success, industry experts said. Reuters visited the premises of P. Tech. Piles of tyres bound in bales, a tall chimney and a filthy pond could be seen behind closed gates. Neighbouring workers told Reuters the firm operated at night and its work produced a stench that would linger until the morning. No one from P. Tech was available for comment. “Tyre pyrolysis is not a problem. The problem is with the mismanagement of it,” Yeo Bee Yin, Malaysia’s environment minister told Reuters when asked about the pyrolysis industry in her country. She noted P. Tech was licensed for pyrolysis but did not speak specifically about the dumping case. Yeo said Malaysia used to have “very lax environmental laws” and “very low punishments” for breaches but has stepped up enforcement recently and closed down some illegal pyrolysis operators in order to better regulate the sector. A labourer sprays water around a reactor at a pyrolysis unit in Jokhabad industrial area in the northern state of Uttar Pradesh, India May 9, 2019. — Reuters pic Backyard operations Malaysia’s department of environment said 22 tyre pyrolysis firms across the country are licensed but declined comment on the number of unlicensed operators. Over half a dozen industry sources said pyrolysis in India, China and South-east Asia also is prevalent mostly in small backyard operations. Earlier this month, Reuters visited a cluster of about 10 tyre burning factories in an industrial area in Jokhabad, a town on the outskirts of India’s capital New Delhi. Mounds of black powder lay on open ground at the first plant, as about half a dozen workers wearing no protection, some barefoot, their clothes and skin stained black, milled about. Most said they lived inside the plant itself, pointing to a cement shed set up barely a few feet away from large, round recycling machines. At a second plant, where a teenager sorted through a pile of odd-sized tyres, plant supervisor Manoj Kumar said he was producing oil mainly used as tar for road construction. While he maintained his plant had high standards, Kumar said most of the other firms in the area were lax, had no mechanism for waste processing and their factories emitted potentially harmful gases in the air. Reuters could not verify his comments. Shops and homes stood barely a kilometre (a half-mile) from the industrial cluster. A report commissioned by Indian environmental rights group SAFE last year said at one site in Jokhabad, carbon fumes and sludge were so bad that monkeys in the surrounding area had black faces and fur. Reuters couldn’t independently confirm its findings. SAFE sent its findings on six plants in a letter to India’s environment ministry in January, and said they were exposing “people at large to environmental risks” and “risking the lives of those involved in such practices for perverse profits.” India’s environment ministry did not respond to a request for comment on the SAFE report. There is no official data on the size of this business, which is being fuelled by a global demand for tyres expected to rise about 3 percent this year to nearly three billion units, according to a report by Cleveland, Ohio-based research firm Freedonia. With free raw material — used tyres — and demand for unconventional oils increasing for everything from tar to build roads to fuel for ships, pyrolysis can be a lucrative business even at a small scale. Asphalt currently sells for about US$100 (RM420) per tonne, while fuel oil sells for about US$400 per tonne. Steel wire recovered after the pyrolysis process of used tyres is seen at a unit in Jokhabad industrial area in the northern state of Uttar Pradesh, India May 9, 2019. — Reuters pic Lax laws Villager Zulkifly Kassim was one of the first to become aware of the dumping of chemicals by P. Tech in the Sungai Kim Kim river in the Malaysian state of Johor on March 7. Shortly after midnight he was awoken by a putrid smell. He went outside to investigate and shone a torchlight into the stream behind his house. “I could see the water already had become black and the fish were coming up and down,” said Zulkifly, 50. Minutes before Zulkifly was awoken, a lorry parked near a bridge upstream from his house and dumped oil waste and sludge into the river, according to the chargesheet filed in court by the police against P. Tech. Over the next few hours and days after the dumping, noxious vapours caused breathing problems, vomiting and dizziness, especially among children and elderly, local authorities said. Selahudeen Aziz, Johor state’s health director, said over 1,200 people were hospitalised with 26 treated in intensive care. Fourteen people were brought to hospital unconscious. The ports around southern Malaysia where the March dumping took place and nearby Singapore make up the world’s most important marine refuelling hub. Two oil traders in Singapore, requesting anonymity, told Reuters that oil from Malaysian tyre pyrolysis had been offered around the market in recent months in the marine oil sector, known as bunker fuel. They said blending such oil into bunker fuels was on the rise as tightening regulations due to come in next year have pushed up benchmark bunker fuel prices to their highest seasonal level in years. — Reuters", "labels": [[59, 67, "GPE"], [109, 122, "GPE"], [124, 129, "GPE"], [130, 141, "DATE"], [143, 169, "ORG"], [171, 177, "DATE"], [236, 244, "GPE"], [300, 317, "CARDINAL"], [325, 342, "DATE"], [515, 532, "ORG"], [665, 670, "LOC"], [676, 680, "LOC"], [682, 687, "GPE"], [692, 697, "GPE"], [742, 747, "CARDINAL"], [751, 760, "ORG"], [882, 884, "CARDINAL"], [1116, 1123, "ORG"], [1150, 1155, "CARDINAL"], [1169, 1176, "ORG"], [1207, 1216, "CARDINAL"], [1266, 1274, "GPE"], [1394, 1401, "PERSON"], [1417, 1421, "DATE"], [1829, 1835, "LOC"], [1840, 1857, "GPE"], [2068, 2075, "GPE"], [2202, 2209, "ORG"], [2231, 2236, "TIME"], [2292, 2303, "TIME"], [2317, 2324, "ORG"], [2353, 2357, "PERSON"], [2445, 2453, "GPE"], [2482, 2489, "ORG"], [2556, 2563, "PERSON"], [2655, 2663, "GPE"], [2940, 2948, "GPE"], [2990, 3003, "GPE"], [3005, 3010, "GPE"], [3011, 3022, "DATE"], [3058, 3066, "GPE"], [3100, 3102, "CARDINAL"], [3216, 3233, "CARDINAL"], [3269, 3274, "GPE"], [3276, 3281, "GPE"], [3286, 3291, "GPE"], [3297, 3301, "LOC"], [3357, 3375, "DATE"], [3377, 3384, "ORG"], [3406, 3414, "CARDINAL"], [3463, 3471, "GPE"], [3500, 3505, "GPE"], [3516, 3525, "GPE"], [3576, 3581, "ORDINAL"], [3592, 3610, "CARDINAL"], [3788, 3805, "QUANTITY"], [3854, 3860, "ORDINAL"], [3944, 3955, "PERSON"], [4074, 4079, "PERSON"], [4235, 4242, "ORG"], [4318, 4327, "QUANTITY"], [4383, 4389, "NORP"], [4417, 4421, "ORG"], [4422, 4431, "DATE"], [4440, 4443, "CARDINAL"], [4452, 4460, "GPE"], [4639, 4642, "CARDINAL"], [4665, 4670, "GPE"], [4697, 4704, "DATE"], [4857, 4862, "GPE"], [4934, 4938, "ORG"], [5072, 5087, "PERCENT"], [5088, 5097, "DATE"], [5101, 5121, "CARDINAL"], [5154, 5163, "GPE"], [5165, 5169, "GPE"], [5190, 5199, "GPE"], [5404, 5411, "ORG"], [5432, 5444, "MONEY"], [5489, 5501, "MONEY"], [5597, 5605, "GPE"], [5647, 5660, "GPE"], [5662, 5667, "GPE"], [5668, 5679, "DATE"], [5695, 5698, "PERSON"], [5713, 5728, "PERSON"], [5744, 5749, "ORDINAL"], [5797, 5804, "PERSON"], [5819, 5826, "PERSON"], [5840, 5849, "NORP"], [5859, 5864, "GPE"], [5868, 5875, "DATE"], [5891, 5899, "TIME"], [5976, 5986, "TIME"], [6113, 6121, "PERSON"], [6123, 6125, "DATE"], [6127, 6134, "TIME"], [6142, 6150, "GPE"], [6330, 6337, "ORG"], [6344, 6362, "TIME"], [6521, 6536, "PERSON"], [6538, 6543, "PERSON"], [6579, 6584, "CARDINAL"], [6615, 6617, "CARDINAL"], [6645, 6653, "CARDINAL"], [6725, 6733, "GPE"], [6744, 6749, "DATE"], [6780, 6789, "GPE"], [6848, 6851, "CARDINAL"], [6867, 6876, "GPE"], [6905, 6912, "ORG"], [6927, 6936, "NORP"], [6990, 7003, "DATE"], [7155, 7164, "DATE"], [7244, 7249, "DATE"]]}
{"text": "THE wheels of justice never stop turning. Throughout history, they have evolved to take into account the changing circumstances of society, the value systems, the opening up of new knowledge frontiers and also technological innovations. But justice in the legal system is a constant, in that it is premised on the firm belief that all men are entitled to equal protection before the law. The administration of justice must be fair and transparent. And, for all civilised societies, justice must always be tempered with mercy. It is in this context that we should examine the statement made by Minister in the Prime Minister's Department Datuk Seri Nazri Aziz about the Government looking into the possibility of abolishing the mandatory death sentence for drug offences. One of the reasons, he said, is that it is difficult to appeal to other countries not to hang Malaysians when our country has the same penalty for the same offences. Close to 250 Malaysians have been arrested as drug mules and sentenced to death abroad, including in China, Venezuela and Peru. But the issue of the death penalty goes beyond that. More than two-thirds of the countries in the world have abolished the death penalty in law or in practice. Of the 58 nations that still have the death penalty in their statutes, only 18 are known to carry out executions. Sadly, Malaysia is among those countries where the death penalty is mandatory for crimes such as murder, possession of firearms, waging war against the King and drug trafficking. Various people, from politicians and lawyers to anti-death penalty advocates, have regularly voiced their views on this issue. So, too, the common folk whose views for and against the death penalty are often determined by some controversial case at that time. Even retired judges have weighed in on the debate and spoken about their personal anguish and difficulty in passing the death sentence. One retired Court of Appeal judge said: “The law is the law but I wish Parliament would abolish the death sentence because if a mistake is made, it would be irreversible. There are other ways of dealing with heinous crimes.” The ball is actually in the court of our august house. It is time our MPs engage in a full debate on the death penalty. If need be, a select committee can be set up to seek the views of as many people as possible. We must have an intelligent discourse on this issue so that we can separate emotions from the facts. It is normal, when emotions run high, for some people to even call for the death penalty to be imposed on snatch thieves, baby dumpers and other lesser criminals. And in any debate on the death penalty, it would also be timely to look into the other parallel issue of mandatory sentences. Again, when the ruling of a particular court case does not resonate with the court of public opinion, there will always be calls to make it mandatory for judges to mete out specific punishment. A mandatory sentence ties the hand of the presiding judge to weigh every offence on its merits, taking into account the circumstances of the case. It does not allow a judge to exhibit compassion even when justice cries out for it. Let us be clear that the death penalty is irreversible, and any miscarriage of justice comes at the very heavy price of a life lost needlessly. And research has also shown that the death penalty has not been an effective deterrent against the crimes it is supposed to minimise. It is time to abolish it.", "labels": [[669, 679, "ORG"], [771, 774, "CARDINAL"], [865, 875, "NORP"], [937, 949, "CARDINAL"], [950, 960, "NORP"], [1038, 1043, "GPE"], [1045, 1054, "GPE"], [1059, 1063, "GPE"], [1118, 1138, "CARDINAL"], [1232, 1234, "CARDINAL"], [1296, 1303, "CARDINAL"], [1346, 1354, "GPE"], [1914, 1917, "CARDINAL"], [1926, 1941, "ORG"], [1985, 1995, "ORG"]]}
{"text": "Lead counsel R. Sivarasa (second left) poses with A. Kugan's mother N. Indra and family members outside the courtroom in Putrajaya December 9, 2013. — Picture by Melissa Chi PUTRAJAYA, Dec 9 – The Court of Appeal today postponed the government’s challenge against the wrongful death suit won by the family of A. Kugan, who died in police detention, to February 28 owing to public interest. Datuk Mohamad Ariff Yusoff, one of three presiding judges, said the court would allow at least one whole day to hear submissions from both sides. “Since it’s a matter of public interest, I’ll give you one to two days, just in case, take your time,” he told the lawyers. On July 1, Home Minister Datuk Seri Dr Ahmad Zahid Hamidi announced the government’s intention to appeal even as Malaysians bay for blood over reports on the alarming number of deaths in police custody — cases similar to Kugan’s controversial death in 2009. In the ruling over the negligence suit brought by Kugan’s family, the High Court on June 26 awarded his mother, N. Indra, RM851,700 in damages for assault and battery, false imprisonment, misfeasance of public office, pain and suffering. Kugan, then 22 years old, was detained as a luxury car theft suspect. He was arrested in Puchong on January 14, 2009 and held overnight at the Puchong Jaya police lock-up before police obtained a remand order. He was taken to the Taipan USJ, Subang Jaya police station two days later for questioning and was found dead four days after that. Former police constable V. Navindran was the only one held responsible for Kugan’s death. Last year, he was convicted and sentenced to three years’ jail. He is currently appealing the conviction. Today, the family’s lead counsel, Sivarasa Rasiah, said the government’s appeal should be dismissed because High Court judge Datuk V.T. Singham gave a “very comprehensive and thorough judgment” analysing all the issues. “We will come here to defend the judgment as a correct judgment, on facts and that the correct award was handed out. “Our position is quite straightforward. Yes, Navindran was part of the group of people who had assaulted but he was not the only one, they were making him a scapegoat to try to whitewash (the case), the judge correctly found that was exactly what was going on that Navindran was used as a scapegoat in a cover up,” he told reporters outside the courtroom. Meanwhile, senior defence counsel Mohd Azizan Mat Ashraf said that the government’s appeal is based on the contention that Sections 7 and 8 of the Civil Law Act 1956 only provide for compensation for estate and exemplary claims. “On our legal point of view, Kugan is not entitled because the law doesn’t allow it because the main issue is that they brought this matter under Section 7 and 8 of the Civil Law Act. “The court has gone about importing these claims which are under the common law claims,” he said, adding that the ruling will be a precedent in Malaysia,” he said. Mohd Azizan said the government is appealing the RM300,000 in exemplary damages, RM50,000 for misfeasance in public office and RM100,000 for false imprisonment. Lawyer Ramesh Sivakumar, who is appealing on behalf of Navindran, said the law does not include damages for misfeasance in public office, which was included in the damages awarded to the claimants. “First time it has come out and the High Court allowed it, whether they are going to affirm it or overturn it, we’ll see. What the judge has done is that he has given ... over and above what is under the law,” he said. He also pointed out that the law was to compensate, and not to punish.", "labels": [[13, 24, "PERSON"], [26, 32, "ORDINAL"], [50, 60, "PERSON"], [68, 76, "PERSON"], [121, 130, "GPE"], [131, 147, "DATE"], [162, 183, "PERSON"], [189, 190, "CARDINAL"], [309, 317, "PERSON"], [352, 363, "DATE"], [390, 403, "PERSON"], [404, 416, "PERSON"], [418, 421, "CARDINAL"], [425, 430, "CARDINAL"], [476, 488, "CARDINAL"], [591, 606, "DATE"], [663, 669, "DATE"], [671, 675, "ORG"], [685, 695, "PERSON"], [699, 717, "PERSON"], [773, 783, "NORP"], [881, 886, "PERSON"], [912, 916, "DATE"], [968, 975, "ORG"], [984, 998, "ORG"], [1002, 1009, "DATE"], [1030, 1038, "PERSON"], [1040, 1049, "PERSON"], [1156, 1161, "PERSON"], [1168, 1180, "DATE"], [1245, 1252, "GPE"], [1256, 1272, "DATE"], [1299, 1311, "LOC"], [1382, 1396, "LOC"], [1398, 1409, "PERSON"], [1425, 1439, "DATE"], [1475, 1484, "DATE"], [1521, 1533, "PERSON"], [1572, 1577, "PERSON"], [1587, 1596, "DATE"], [1632, 1643, "DATE"], [1693, 1698, "DATE"], [1710, 1712, "ORG"], [1727, 1742, "ORG"], [1763, 1765, "ORG"], [1801, 1811, "ORG"], [1818, 1836, "PERSON"], [2075, 2084, "PERSON"], [2295, 2304, "PERSON"], [2420, 2442, "PERSON"], [2509, 2519, "LAW"], [2524, 2525, "CARDINAL"], [2529, 2551, "LAW"], [2644, 2649, "PERSON"], [2761, 2770, "LAW"], [2780, 2797, "LAW"], [2943, 2951, "GPE"], [2963, 2974, "PERSON"], [3124, 3147, "ORG"], [3179, 3188, "GPE"], [3323, 3328, "ORDINAL"], [3354, 3368, "ORG"]]}
{"text": "Datuk Seri Anwar Ibrahim told CNN he believed MH370’s Captain Zaharie Ahmad was opposed to extremism and fanaticism. — Picture by Choo Choy May KUALA LUMPUR, March 20 — Captain Zaharie Ahmad Shah, the Malaysia Airlines (MAS) pilot now in the centre of investigations on missing Flight MH370, was opposed to extremism and fanaticism, according to Datuk Seri Anwar Ibrahim. Anwar, who has admitted to knowing the 53-year-old pilot to some degree, told CNN’s Christiane Amanpour in an interview aired this morning that Zaharie had merely been an ardent supporter of the federal opposition’s cause, which he stressed was about “democratic reform”. “Certainly he is not,” Anwar said when asked if he believed Zaharie to be a fanatic. “He supports our multi-racial coalition. He supports democratic reform. He is against any form of extremism,” he said in the interview, which was aired at 3am this morning. “And we take a very strong position in clamouring for change through constitutional and democratic means.” As hours turned into days and days into nearly two weeks now, answers to why and how the Boeing 777 wide-body aircraft had gone missing the morning of March 8 have grown even more scant. Investigators have been relying on what could best be described as piecemeal evidence gathered from data weaned off the defence systems of several nations. What the authorities finally agreed on — one week after MH370’s disappearance — is that the plane, which had been bound for Beijing from Malaysia’s capital city here, had veered suddenly westwards in mid-flight. The changed flight path had been deliberate, according to Malaysian officials on Saturday. The revelation sent investigators back to the drawing board as they refocused their probe on the backgrounds of those on board flight MH370 — all 227 passengers and 12 crew members. And suddenly Zaharie, the veteran MAS pilot who had earlier been described as “passionate” about flying, became a key concern. Local police searched the homes of Zaharie and that of his co-pilot Fariq Ab Hamid last Saturday, taking away the former’s home-built flight simulator for inspection. Today, local and foreign experts, including those from the US’s Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) are poring over data installed in the simulator and trying to retrieve whatever information the pilot had deleted. But this could take days or even weeks, CNN reported this morning. Anwar, whose link to the pilot suddenly surfaced amid media scrutiny on the latter’s background, confirmed to reporters yesterday that the man was related to his daughter-in-law. He was asked again to speak on the link by Amanpour and the leader said his daughter-in-law called the MAS pilot “uncle”. Amanpour, quoting from Anwar’s press secretary, had asked the Pakatan Rakyat (PR) de facto chief to confirm if Zaharie was indeed his “son’s wife’s mother’s father’s brother’s son”. “What my daughter-in-law told me is that he is a family member, not too close, but she calls him ‘uncle,’ which is quite common here. But I know him... basically as a party activist,” Anwar replied. He appeared as well to dismiss links between Zaharie and his sodomy II case, in which he had been sentenced to five years in jail just hours before MH370 went missing. Anwar said that based on what he gathered from the pilot’s colleagues, Zaharie had indeed been “disturbed” by the court’s decision. But he was quick to add that “many others were disturbed”. “I mean, we were shocked and appalled by the speed of the process of the court of appeal.” “But I think that’s quite normal. I don’t think it’s something that would trigger a person of his expertise, calibre, to do any unwanted activity. I am absolutely certain of that,” Anwar said, according to CNN’s report.", "labels": [[0, 24, "PERSON"], [30, 33, "ORG"], [46, 53, "ORG"], [62, 75, "PERSON"], [130, 139, "PERSON"], [158, 166, "DATE"], [177, 195, "PERSON"], [197, 218, "ORG"], [278, 290, "PRODUCT"], [346, 370, "PERSON"], [372, 377, "PERSON"], [450, 453, "ORG"], [456, 475, "PERSON"], [498, 510, "TIME"], [516, 523, "PERSON"], [667, 672, "PERSON"], [704, 711, "PERSON"], [884, 900, "TIME"], [1030, 1034, "DATE"], [1039, 1043, "DATE"], [1049, 1065, "DATE"], [1098, 1104, "ORG"], [1105, 1108, "PRODUCT"], [1145, 1167, "TIME"], [1393, 1401, "DATE"], [1408, 1415, "ORG"], [1476, 1483, "GPE"], [1489, 1497, "GPE"], [1622, 1631, "NORP"], [1645, 1653, "DATE"], [1789, 1796, "ORG"], [1801, 1804, "CARDINAL"], [1820, 1822, "CARDINAL"], [1850, 1857, "PERSON"], [1999, 2006, "PERSON"], [2032, 2046, "PERSON"], [2047, 2060, "DATE"], [2131, 2136, "DATE"], [2186, 2226, "ORG"], [2228, 2231, "ORG"], [2368, 2372, "DATE"], [2381, 2386, "DATE"], [2388, 2391, "ORG"], [2401, 2413, "TIME"], [2415, 2420, "PERSON"], [2497, 2499, "PERSON"], [2535, 2544, "DATE"], [2637, 2645, "PERSON"], [2697, 2700, "ORG"], [2716, 2724, "PERSON"], [2739, 2746, "ORG"], [2774, 2792, "FAC"], [2827, 2834, "PERSON"], [3082, 3087, "PERSON"], [3142, 3149, "PERSON"], [3165, 3167, "PERSON"], [3208, 3218, "DATE"], [3227, 3237, "TIME"], [3245, 3250, "NORP"], [3265, 3270, "PERSON"], [3336, 3343, "PERSON"], [3384, 3386, "ORG"], [3728, 3733, "PERSON"], [3753, 3756, "ORG"]]}
